Curriculum Vitae

Name: - Santu Bhattacharya

Mobile No.:- +91-6386997929,+91-9889836662

Address: - 209, Colonelganj, Prayagraj - 211002.

Post Applied for :- PGT English

Job Objective



- 1. "To secure a position as a teacher and utilize my dedication to foster quality education required for a child's development."
- 2. "Develop and promote creativity and high-order thinking skills that increase the performance of the students."
- 3. "To build a long-term profession as a teacher that will offer endless opportunities for career growth and to keep up with cutting-edge educational technologies."
- 4. "To obtain a teaching position in special education which will allow me to utilise my interest and passion for student development combined with skills and experience that will enable me to make a significant contribution at school."
- 5. "Seeking a teaching position as an English teacher to share my passion for the subject as well as enlighten young minds to gain proficiency in this language."
- 6. "To obtain a teaching position where I can utilise my knowledge of advanced teaching methods such as team learning and e-learning."
- 7. "Passionate, Creative and Certified teacher with a bachelor's degree in Education and a zeal to foster holistic education and learning to children of all ages."
- 8. "Qualified and resourceful teacher with a master's degree in English and proven knowledge of educational technology, blended online learning and curriculum design.

Educational Qualifications

Exam	Year	Board/University	Subjects	Division	Percentage of Marks
High School (Erny Memorial School, Prayagraj)	2008	C.B.S.E.	Science, Social Science, Hindi, English, Maths	Second Division	56%
Intermediate (Tilak Shikshan Sansthan)	2014	C.B.S.E.	Physics, Chemistry, Maths, English, Hindi	Second Division	50%
Graduation (B.A)	2017	University Of Allahabad	English Lit., Sociology	Second Division	50%
Post Graduation (M.A.)	2019	University Of Allahabad (Dept. Of English and M.E.L.)	English Literature	First Division	74.385%

Professional Qualifications

Exam		Year	College/University	Subjects	Division	Percentage
Bachelor	Of	2022	Department of	Compulsory	First Division	78%
Education			Teacher Education,	Subjects +		
(B.Ed)			Ewing Christian	Pedagogy of		
			College, affiliated to	English and		
			the University Of	Political		
			Allahabad.	Sciences/Civics		

Work Experience:

- 1 Years experience in **The Legend Hotel**, Prayagraj, as a Front Office Executive and Reservation Executive. (2018-19)
- 7 Months Experience from **Hotel Kanha Shyam**, Allahabad, as Reservations Executive (2019)
- 1 years Experience in **The Landmark Towers**, Kanpur as both Reservations and Front office executive (2019-2020)
- 1 years experience in Laurels International School, Prayagraj (affiliated to the C.B.S.E.) as a English Teacher (PGT) (2020-21).
- Currently working in **Benhur High School & College**, **Prayagraj (affliated to the C.I.S.C.E.)** as PGT English. (August 2022 to present).

Extra Curricular Activities:

- Actively participated in the Scout and Guide programme organized by the Department of Teacher's Education, Ewing Christian College, Prayagraj.
- Actively participated in Seminars and Symposium while pursuing Graduation, Post Graduation and B.Ed.
- Participated in various competitions like oral presentation poster making competition, flower gardening, Yoga, Singing, and Bible quiz competitions, etc.

Personal Profile

Name : Santu Bhattacharya

Father's Name : Late. Nilendu Bhattacharya

Mother's Name : Lavanya Bhattacharya

Date of Birth : 30-09-1992

Marital Status : Unmarried

Sex : Male

Email Id : niloysantu@gmail.com

Nationality : Indian
Religion : Hindu

Language Known: Hindi, English, and Bengali.

Other Skills

- Strong Knowledge of utilizing all the modern teaching aids.
- Computer Skills, MS Word, Excel, Internet Browsing.
- Expertise in using new teaching methodology to explain difficult topics.
- **50+ WPM typing speed** on MS Office.

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information furnished by me is correct and true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date	

Place: Prayagraj (Santu Bhattacharya)